The maximum force of the future.
Mad Max is a adventure, action, thriller film directed by George Miller.
In the ravaged near-future, a savage motorcycle gang rules the road.
Terrorizing innocent civilians while tearing up the streets, the ruthless gang
laughs in the face of a police force hell-bent on stopping them.
Max Rockatansky, played by Mel Gibson.
Jessie Rockatansky, played by Joanne Samuel.
Toecutter, played by Hugh Keays-Byrne.
Jim Goose, played by Steve Bisley.
Johnny the Boy, played by Tim Burns.
Fifi, played by Roger Ward.
Mad Max is a 1979 Australian dystopian action film directed by George Miller in his directorial debut, who
co-wrote the screenplay with James McCausland, based on a story by Miller and Byron Kennedy.
Mel Gibson stars as "Mad" Max Rockatansky, a police officer turned vigilante in a
dystopian near-future Australia in the midst of societal collapse.
Joanne Samuel, Hugh Keays-Byrne, Steve Bisley, Tim Burns and
Roger Ward also appear in supporting roles.
Principal photography for Mad Max took place in and
around Melbourne and lasted for six weeks.
The film initially received a polarised reception upon its release
in April 1979, although it won four AACTA Awards.
Filmed on a budget of A$400,000, it earned more than US$100 million worldwide in
gross revenue and set a Guinness record for most profitable film.
The success of Mad Max has been credited for further opening
the global market to Australian New Wave films.
Mad Max became the first in the series, giving rise to three sequels: Mad Max 2
(1981), Mad Max Beyond Thunderdome (1985) and Mad Max: Fury Road (2015).
A spin-off film titled Furiosa: A Mad Max Saga was released in 2024.
The film explores themes of australia, petrol, baby, chain, dystopia.
The tone is thought_provoking and intense.